Guide to the Feg Murray Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Feg Murray papers
1907-2001
1915-1974
SC0755
Murray, Feg
6 Linear feet
This collection primarily documents his career as an illustrator, but also includes materials relating to his athletic career and his family. Collection includes correspondence, primarily to his future wife Dorothy Hanna, 1919 and undated; clippings and photographs pertaining to his track career, 1915-20; photographs of Murray, his family, and Murray with Hollywood actors; and original artwork and published illustrations and drawings, 1907-1962. Subjects of his artwork include Stanford student life (including "Snoppyquops" drawings and verse), athletes, Hollywood stars, European trip, and World War I cartoons. Also included is a copy of the book HOLLY-WOULD!, text by John Milton Hagen and illustrations by Feg Murray (Arlington House, 1974).
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Frederic (Feg) Murray earned his A.B. in graphic arts at Stanford University in 1916; he married Dorothy Hanna (Stanford class of 1919) in 1920. Artist, writer, and syndicated cartoonist, Murray was perhaps best know for his "Seein' Stars" column. He was also a track athlete, competing on the Stanford University team and in the 1920 Olympics.
Description of the Collection
This collection primarily documents his career as an illustrator, but also includes materials relating to his athletic career and his family. Collection includes correspondence, primarily to his future wife Dorothy Hanna, 1919 and undated; clippings and photographs pertaining to his track career, 1915-20; photographs of Murray, his family, and Murray with Hollywood actors; and original artwork and published illustrations and drawings, 1907-1962. Subjects of his artwork include Stanford student life (including "Snoppyquops" drawings and verse), athletes, Hollywood stars, European trip, and World War I cartoons. Also included is a copy of the book HOLLY-WOULD!, text by John Milton Hagen and illustrations by Feg Murray (Arlington House, 1974).
Access Terms
Murray, Feg; Athletes --Pictorial works.; Illustrators --United States.; Motion picture actors and actresses --Pictorial works.; Track and field.
Collection Contents
- Papers
  - Athletic career, clippings, 1915 and undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Athletic career, clippings, 1915-16 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Athletic career, clippings, 1916 and undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Athletic career, P.A. team, photographs (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Athletic career, action shots, photographs (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Athletic career, action shots, photographs (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Athletic career, S.U. teams and individuals, photographs (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Athletics, clippings on 1920 Olympics (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Athletics, Olympics, photographs (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Athletics, photo album, 1920 Olympics (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Athletics, Panama-Pacific International Exposition, August 7, 1915 program (track meet) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Biographical materials (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Biographical materials (original clippings) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Calendars with Murray's illustration, 1907, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, personal (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, notes to Dorothy (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, letters to Dorothy, 1919 and undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, letters to Dorothy, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence and contract re Holly-Would 1973 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Greeting cards with Murray's images (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Murray Christmas cards (from the Murrays with Murray images) (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Murray, Dorothy Hanna, clippings (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Murray on the Internet, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Murray's articles on CA sports, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Original art: Anything Can Happen in Golf (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Original art: athletics (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Original art: "Double Exposures" (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Original art: drawings of family (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Original art: Life Saver man in raincoat (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Original art: watercolor of man in Guatemala 1962 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Original art: Stanford images (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Original art: various images (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Photographs of Murray's art work (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Photographs, family, early years (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Photographs, family, later years (1 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Photographs, family, later years (2 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Photographs, family portraits and informal portraits (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Photographs, family, negatives (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Photographs, F. Murray (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Photographs, negatives of 2 Hollywood images (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Photographs, Perry McDonald (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Printed work: Individual athletes (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Printed work: Sports (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Printed work: Stanford images (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Printed work: Street and Smiths Sport Story Magazine covers (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Printed work: World War I cartoon (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Facts on Hollywood Figures #1-19, camera-ready copy, 1945-46 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Facts on Hollywood Figures #20-50, camera-ready copy, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Radio broadcast script, Seein' Stars in Hollywood 1937 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Seein' Stars #1-19 [numbers reflect order in the book Holly-Would] (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Seein' Stars #20-39 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Seein' Stars #40-59 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Seein' Stars #60-79 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Seein' Stars #80-96 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Seein' Stars, miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - World War I French language booklet for soldiers, 1917 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Printing die for 1930 image (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - John Milton Hagen, Holly-Would!, illustrations by Feg Murray (Arlington House, 1974) (Box 2)
  - Snoppyquop drawings and verses:
    - Atterbury Snoppyquops (Box 3)
    - The Boys and Girls Newspaper, 1924 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Calendar border (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - The Centaur-Field – verse and drawing (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Ice-o-Therm – verse (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - List of Snoppyquops for book (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Newsprint Snoppyquops (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Original art (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Original art (including watercolor of Murray "getting" the mosquito) (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Printed Snoppyquops with text (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Printed images, no text (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Scrapbook page with attached verse (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Scrapbook pages of Snoppyquop items (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Snoppyquop illustrations (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Snoppyquops No. 1-23 (incomplete) (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Verse, with drawings (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Verses, manuscript (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Verses, typed (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Cartoon of anniversary of Mr. and Mrs. John W. Ballard (original art), 1922 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Charlie Chapman drawing (printed with hand-drawing additions) (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Christmas cards by Murray (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Drawing of a woman (newsprint version) (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - European sketches (original art: ink and watercolor) (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - European sketches, Greece and Italy (original art: pencil, colored pencil, ink, watercolor) (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Family photographs (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Original drawings (valentine cartoon, hands, Abe Lincoln) (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Original drawings, sports (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Original envelopes from letters to Dorothy (letters in Box 1) (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Ostrich head drawing (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Photograph from a track meet (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Published images (1928 calendar, Chaparral cover) (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Saturday Evening Post cover, possibly sketch of Murray by John Falter, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Sports – cartoons and drawings (newsprint) (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Sports - cartoons and drawings (published) (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - W. C. Fields, drawing of (original artwork) (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Hollywood Photographs: mostly Murray posed with stars of the 1930s and 1940s
    - Unidentified negative (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Murray with soldiers (?) in a hospital (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Murray and actors on set (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Murray at "isolation table" (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Heather Angel (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Joan Bennett (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - George Brent (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Joe E. Brown (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Jim Burke (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Carl Busson (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - James Cagney (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Eddie Cantor (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Joan Crawford (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Marion Davies (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Delores Del Rio (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Irene Dunn (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Errol Flynn (?) (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Cary Grant (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Helen Hayes (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Bob Hope and Bing Crosby (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Marsha Hunt (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Margaret Lindsay (?) (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Carole Lombard (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Anita Louise (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Jeannette McDonald (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Fred MacMurray (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Victor Mature (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Ozzie Nelson, Harriet Nelson (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Pat O'Brien (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Maureen O'Sullivan (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Jean Parker (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Nat Pendleton (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Jack Pierce (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Lyda Roberti (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Mae Robeson (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Will Rogers (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Randy Scott (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Spencer Tracy (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Lynton and Fay Wells (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Jane Withers (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Loretta Young (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Linda Darnell (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Una Merkle (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Ann Southern (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Unidentified Hollywood photographs (Box 6)
  - Album containing examples of Snoppyquops drawings, two Hollywood photographs, and a Murray Christmas card (Box 6)
  - Assorted World War I sketches/cartoons (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Color sketches/cartoons (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Mounted copies of WWI cartoons (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Possible pages from album (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Album "To Bay from Feg 24 Cartoons on his 24th Birthday". Only 5 drawings are still attached in the binding; subject is World War I experiences. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Oversize:
    - Original drawings (1 cartoon, 1 Snoppyquops) (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Original drawings – sports (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Seein' Stars – original drawings (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Seein' Stars – printed versions (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Seein' Stars – newsprint versions (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Oversize:
    - Assorted drawings (2 printed items, 1 original cartoon on the 54 wedding anniversary of unnamed couple) (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Murraymento for Editors (examples of Murray's artwork) (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Broadside advertisement for Murray's sports writings (Box 10, Folder 3)